lawnsite.com 2017-12-16

# Privacy Policy | Grand View Media

#### PRIVACY POLICY

LAST UPDATED: April 3, 2017

Grand View Media Group, Inc. (“Grand View Media” or “we”) respects your privacy and is committed to protecting it through our compliance with this policy.

Grand View Media wants you to have a positive experience at the websites we operate. We want you to know that we respect the privacy and security of our users. Our goal is to provide you with an experience that delivers the information, resources and services that are helpful to you. In order to achieve this goal, we may collect information from you. We discuss our information collection practices below. This Privacy Policy sets forth the privacy principles we follow, in accordance with our operations.

This Privacy Policy sets forth the privacy practices in effect at Grand View Media’s websites (the “Websites”) and for information collected through the purchase of our products. If you do not agree to these terms, do not access these Websites.

Contact Information:  Attn: Customer Service Dept. 200 Croft Street, Suite 1, Birmingham, AL 35242; Telephone: 1-888-431-2877; email us by visiting <http://grandviewmedia.com/contact/>

##### What Information Is Collected and How is it Used?

A. What Information Do We Collect?

  1. **Personal Information:** information that identifies you as an individual or relates to an identifiable individual, including: name, title, company name, job function, expertise, postal address, telephone number, or email address. If you submit any Personal Information relating to other people to us or to our service providers in connection with the Sites, you represent that you have the authority to do so and to permit us to use the information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
  2. **Non-Personal Information:** any information that does not reveal your specific identity or does not directly relate to an identifiable individual. This might include IP addresses and web server log files to track trends, administer the Websites, track user movement, and gather demographic information, and information collected through cookies.

It is not our regular practice to collect “Sensitive Information,” such as Personal Information specifying medical or health conditions, racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership or information specifying the sex life of the individual. If we collect Sensitive Information from you, we commit that we will not disclose it to any third parties, including our affiliates or Contractors, or use that information for purposes that you believe may be incompatible with the purpose for which it originally was collected (as permitted by this policy) unless you expressly tell us that we can disclose that information or use it for those different purposes. In order for us to disclose it or use it for those purposes, you must contact us to inform us that you do will permit these uses of your Sensitive Information. To do so, please contact us by mail or email at the address or email address provided above.

B. How Do We Collect the Information?

We will only collect and use Personal Information when a user voluntarily provides it to us or when an institution provides it to us in connection with its method of authenticating users for access to our products. In order to use some portions of our Websites, or in order to undertake certain actions (such as setting up an account to make a purchase of an article), a user must first complete a registration form or provide an e-mail address that will require disclosure of Personal Information. Such disclosure is strictly voluntary. In order to contact us by e-mail, however, you must provide an e-mail address.

We collect and use non-Personal Information, including IP addresses and web server log files to track trends, administer the Websites, track user movement, and gather demographic information. We use this non-Personal Information in the aggregate. We do not combine these types of non-Personal Information with Personal Information. We may also share aggregated demographic information with our business partners, sponsors, advertisers, and companies that control, are controlled by, or are under common control with Grand View Media.

Cookies:  We may place a “cookie” or other tracking or information gathering device used in the industry in the browser files of a user’s computer. A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’s hard drive containing information about the user.  We use cookies to collect information about your use of our Websites, which enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our website.  We also use cookies from third party for marketing purposes (such as interest-based online advertising) that allow us to display Grand View Media promotional material to you on other sites you visit across the internet partners based on your visit to our Websites (e.g. Remarketing with Google Analytics, Google Display Network Impression Reporting, and Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting).  Third party cookies are covered by the third party’s privacy policy.

Users can set their browsers or third party software to reject cookies. If a user rejects the cookie, the user may be unable to use portions of our Websites. Some of the Websites provide links to also may use cookies. We have no control over these linked websites or access to or control over cookies or other technology used by linked websites.

The following is a list of the cookies that may be used across the Websites:

**Type** | **Name** | **Purpose**  
---|---|---  
Analytics Cookie | Google Analytics | A third-party cookie provided by Google, Inc. that collects aggregate statistical data about how visitors use the site (i.e., what pages users visit, how long they are on the website, how they got there and what they click on) so that we can improve the user experience and serve up the content our visitors find most useful.  They do not collect or store Personal Information. 

You can find out more about Google’s privacy policy concerning its analytics service at [Google privacy policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/).

Google also offers a tool that allows you to opt-out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites and can be found [here](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).  
  
Analytics Cookie | Marketing automation webtracking cookie (Munchkin, RTP) | A third-party cookie provided by Marketo Inc. that recognize you as a unique user when you return to our website, and to track various data related to your website usage in order to provide custom content or services related to your specific interests.  The Marketo Munchkin and RTP cookies collect information about your computer and your visits to our marketing web pages such as your IP address, geographical location, browser type, referral source, length of visit and pages viewed. 

The cookies placed by the Marketo server are readable only by Marketo. For more information on Marketo cookies and what they are used for, visit Marketo’s [Cookie policy page](http://www.marketo.com/trust/legal/cookies/) and [privacy page](http://www.marketo.com/trust/legal/privacy/) for more information.  
  
Advertising Cookie | DoubleClick by Google (Ad Platform) | A third-party cookie provided by Google, Inc. that collects data about your activities on Grand View Media Websites and other websites to provide you targeted advertising, but does not personally or directly identify you.   This information may be used in combination with the data collected through the other cookies listed above. 

You can find out more about Google’s privacy policy concerning its advertising features at [Google privacy policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/).

You can opt-out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites [here](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). You can also opt out with [Ad Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/anonymous?sig=ACi0TCjR4sMQxSJOzB_v8TNsRdxQm9IOWavuDzrTGX3ANa8kqL6ITAuvJTz80Gcsh_l-z6OoMveMxAUAhfjoO1OxDTVkXfwPgey3tRsdJsgMeZ6oDRf0Wb8&hl=en) or the [NAI’s consumer opt-out](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/#completed).  
  
Advertising Cookie | Live Intent | Live Intent may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser to enable you to receive customized ads, content or services.    No personally identifiable information is placed into these cookies.  The cookies may reflect de-identified demographic or other data linked to data you voluntarily have submitted to us, e.g., your email address, in hashed, non-human readable form. To opt-out of these cookies or learn more please go to <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>.  
Advertising Cookie | AdDaptive Intelligence | Collect, anonymous, Non-Personally Identifiable Information (“Non-PII”). Non-PII is information that cannot by itself be used to identify a particular person or entity, and may include your IP host address, pages viewed, browser type, Internet browsing and usage habits, Internet Service Provider, domain name, the time/date of your visit to this Website, the referring URL and your computer’s operating system. We collect this Non-PII data in order to deliver more relevant advertising to internet users. http://www.addaptive.com/privacy/  
  
* * *

Grand View Media’s Websites may use social media features, such as the Facebook ‘like’ button (“Social Media Features”). These features may collect your IP address and which page you are visiting on our Websites, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. You may be given the option by such Social Media Features to post information about your activities on our Websites to a profile page of yours that is provided by a third party Social Media network in order to share with others within your network. Social Media Features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on the Company’s Web site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing the relevant Social Media Features.

Web Beacons:  Grand View Media uses web beacons alone or in conjunction with cookies to compile information about customers’ and visitors’ usage of our Websites and interaction with emails from Grand View Media. Web beacons are clear electronic images that can recognize certain types of information on your computer, such as cookies, when you viewed a particular websites tied to the web beacon, and a description of a websites tied to the web beacon.  As with cookies, you can use your browser or app settings to control web beacons.

C. How Do We Use the Information?

We use information that we collect about you or you provide to us, including personal information, to:

  * Present our Websites and its contents to you and notify you of any changes
  * Provide you with requested information, products, or services
  * Provide you with notices related to your account or transactions
  * Carry out obligations and enforce our rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and us, including billing and collection
  * Provide interactive features for your participation
  * Fulfill any and all other purposes for which you provide it or to which you consent

We may also use this information to contact you about our own and third party goods or services that may be of interest to you. If you do not want us to use your information in this way, please check the relevant box located on the form on which we collect your data or adjust your user account preferences. For more information, see Section F of this Policy (What Choices Do I Have?).

We may also use this information to display advertisements to our advertisers’ target audiences. While we do not disclose your personal information for these purposes without your consent, clicking on or otherwise interacting with an advertisement may indicate to the advertiser that you meet its target criteria.

We may disclose aggregated information about users and information that does not identify any individual, without restriction.

We may disclose personal information collected as described in this Privacy Policy to: our affiliates; contractors, service providers, and other third parties used to support our business; third parties contractually bound to obligations of confidentiality and use, to market their products or services if you have consented to/not opted out of these disclosures. (For more information, see Section F of this Policy (What Choices Do I Have?)); fulfill the purpose for which you provide it, such as an “email a friend” feature; or any other purpose disclosed by us when you provide information; or with your consent.

We also reserve the right to disclose your Personal Information if we are required to do so by law, or in the good faith belief that disclosure of the information is reasonably necessary to comply with legal process, to respond to claims, or to protect or advance the rights, property, safety, or well-being of our company, our employees, customers, or the public.

In the unlikely event that all of Grand View Media Group’s assets or substantially all of its assets are acquired, customer information, which may include Personal Information, may be one of the transferred assets.

D. How Do We Secure Personal Information?

To secure your personal information from accidental loss or unauthorized access, use, alteration, or disclosure, all information you provide to us is stored on secure servers behind firewalls. Any payment transactions will be encrypted using SSL technology.  Grand View Media provides links to third-party websites. These websites may not have the same privacy policies as Grand View Media. We take reasonable care in recommending these websites but we are not responsible for their content or privacy policies. We urge users to read the privacy statement of a third-party website when leaving our site and linking to a third-party website.

We always use industry-standard encryption technologies when transferring and receiving consumer data exchanged with our site. We have appropriate security measures in place in our physical facilities to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information that we have collected from you at our site.

E. How Can I Access, Correct, Amend or Remove Information About Me?

We want to assure you that you have access to your Personal Information that we collect and store. Customers may correct or amend information, or delete information that is inaccurate, or prevent their information from being used for purposes other than those for which it was originally collected. To do so, please contact us by written request or e-mail at the contact information stated above.

F. What Choices Do I Have?

We strive to provide you with choices regarding the personal information you provide us. To exercise control over your information, we have provided you with the following mechanisms:

  * **Tracking Technologies and Advertising.** You can adjust your browser settings to manage cookies. To manage Flash cookie settings, visit the Flash player settings page on [Adobe’s website](http://help.adobe.com/en_US/FlashPlayer/LSM/WS6aa5ec234ff3f285139dc56112e3786b68c-7fff.html#WS6aa5ec234ff3f285139dc56112e3786b68c-7ffe) (See Section B of this Privacy Policy for more information)
  * **Disclosure of Your Information for Third-Party Advertising.** You can opt-out of information sharing by adjusting your account preferences or contacting us requesting that we not share personal information for promotional purposes by mail or email at the address or email address provided above.
  * **Promotional Offers from Grand View Media.** If you do not want to receive promotions from us or third parties, you can opt out by adjusting your account preferences or contacting us requesting that we not contact you by mail or email at the address or email address provided above.
  * **Targeted Advertising.** If you do not want us to deliver advertisements according to our advertisers’ target-audience preferences, you can opt-out by adjusting your account preferences or contact us by mail or email at the address or email address provided above. You can also adjust your Google [Ads Settings.](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en)

We do not control third parties’ collection or use of your information to serve interest-based advertising. However, these parties may provide opt-out options, such as the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/#completed).

G. Collection and Use of Information from Children

Our Websites are not intended for children under 13 years of age. No one under age 13 may provide any personal information to or on the Website. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If you are under 13, do not use or provide any information on this Website or on or through any of its features. If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us using the information listed above.

##### Questions

If you have any questions, comments, or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy or our practices, please send us an e-mail or write to us at the addresses listed above.

##### Changes to Privacy Policy

We will notify you of changes to this Privacy Policy by posting an updated policy on this page. You agree that continued use of the Websites is an acknowledgment and consent to any terms contained in this Privacy Policy, current at the time of use.

##### Miscellaneous

_Do Not Track Signals_ : Grand View Media does not recognize automated browser signals regarding tracking mechanisms, which may include ‘do not track’ instructions.

_California Privacy Rights_ :  California Civil Code Section § 1798.83 allows California residents to request certain information regarding disclosure of information to third parties for direct marketing purposes. To do so, please write us at Grand View Media, 200 Croft Street, Suite 1, Birmingham, AL 35242.
